{"name": "56B  2001-1", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The lowest temperature on a winter morning was -8\u00b0F. Later that same day the temperature reached a high of 24\u00b0 F. By how many degrees Fahrenheit did the temperature increase?", "choices": {"A": "3\u00b0", "B": "8\u00b0", "C": "16\u00b0", "D": "24\u00b0", "E": "32\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Disregarding sales tax, how much will you save when you buy an $11 compact disc that is on sale for 25% off?", "choices": {"A": "$0.28", "B": "$0.44", "C": "$2.75", "D": "$3.00", "E": "$8.25"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. As part of a school project, Akio wants to find the average cost of renting a newly released videotape from video rental stores in his neighborhood. He surveys 4 stores and finds the cost of renting a newly released videotape from the 4 stores to be $3.50, $3.40, $3.50, and $3.00, respectively. Using this data, what is the average cost of renting a newly released videotape from these 4 stores?", "choices": {"A": "$3.25", "B": "$3.30", "C": "$3.35", "D": "$3.45", "E": "$3.50"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. In the figure below, AC is parallel to DE with X on AC and B on DE. Also AB \u224c BC, and the measure of \u2220XAB is 110\u00b0 . What is the measure of \u2220ACB ?", "choices": {"A": "35\u00b0", "B": "40\u00b0", "C": "55\u00b0", "D": "70\u00b0", "E": "110\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. Regular hexagon ABCDEF is inscribed in a circle, as shown below. If the length of radius OD is 15 centimeters, how long is AB, in centimeters?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "18", "C": "30", "D": "5\u03c0", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. The price of a pumpkin is directly proportional to its weight. If a pumpkin that weighs 15.0 pounds costs $3.25, how much will an 11.4-pound pumpkin cost?", "choices": {"A": "$0.95", "B": "$1.23", "C": "$1.95", "D": "$2.47", "E": "$4.28"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. In the figure below, D is a point on AB, and CD is perpendicular to AB. Based on this information, which of the following is the best conclusion?", "choices": {"A": "\u2220CDA \u224c \u2220CDB.", "B": "\u2220CDA is larger than \u2220CDB.", "C": "AB bisects CD.", "D": "CD and DB are equal in length.", "E": "Point C is equidistant from A and B."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. If 3x - 7 = 4x - 16, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "-23", "B": "-9", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "9"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Which of the following is always equal to a(5 - a) - 6(a + 4) ?", "choices": {"A": "-2a - 24", "B": "-2a + 4", "C": "-a2 - a - 24", "D": "-a2 - a + 4", "E": "-2a3 - 24"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. One marble is drawn at random from a bag containing 3 red, 2 blue, and 4 green marbles. What is the probability that the marble drawn is NOT blue?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Wanda programs her calculator to perform a linear function, but she doesn't tell you what that function is. When n = 6, the value of the function is 2. When n = 12, the value is 4. Which of the following expressions explains what the calculator will display when any number, n, is entered ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "n - 4", "C": "n - 8", "D": "2n - 10", "E": "2n - 20"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. On the line segment below, the ratio of lengths XY to YZ is 1 : 3. What is the ratio of XY to XZ ?", "choices": {"A": "1 : 4", "B": "1 : 2", "C": "3 : 1", "D": "4 : 1", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. If a board 7 feet 10 inches long is cut into 2 equal parts, as shown below, what will be the length, to the nearest inch, of each part ?", "choices": {"A": "3\u2032 5\u2033", "B": "3\u2032 9\u2033", "C": "3\u2032 11\u2033", "D": "4\u2032 2\u2033", "E": "4\u2032 5\u2033"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. The speed of one train exceeds twice the speed of another by 30 mph. If r mph is the speed of the slower train, which of the following expresses the speed, in miles per hour, of the faster train?", "choices": {"A": "r + 15", "B": "r - 30", "C": "r + 30", "D": "2r - 30", "E": "2r + 30"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. The circle shown below has a radius of 10 meters, and the length of chord AB is 16 meters. If O marks the center of the circle, what is the length of OC ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "6", "C": "12", "D": "", "E": "36"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. What is the value of the expression x3 - 2x2 + 4x + 4 for x = -2 ?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "-2", "C": "-4", "D": "-8", "E": "-20"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. What is the next term after  in the geometric sequence 16, -4, 1, , . . . \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "0", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. On the blueprint for Betty's house,  inch represents an actual length of 1 foot. What is the area, in square feet, of Betty's rectangular bedroom, which is inches by 3 inches on the blueprint ?", "choices": {"A": "30", "B": "44", "C": "60", "D": "120", "E": "244"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. If a &gt; 0 and b &lt; 0, then the sum of a and b:", "choices": {"A": "is always positive.", "B": "is always negative.", "C": "is always zero.", "D": "cannot be zero, but can be any other real number.", "E": "can be any real number."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. If x +  = , then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "21", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. What is the slope of the line given by the equation 3x + 5y = -15 ?", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "3", "E": "5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. The length of a side of a square is represented as (2x - 3) inches. Which of the following general expressions represents the area of the square, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "4x2 - 12x + 9", "B": "4x2 - 12x + 6", "C": "4x2 - 6x + 9", "D": "4x2 - 9", "E": "8x - 12"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Which of the following is a polynomial factor of x2 - 2x - 15 ?", "choices": {"A": "15 - x", "B": "5 + x", "C": "3 + x", "D": "2 - x", "E": "x"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. In the equation m = , q represents a positive integer. As q gets larger and larger without bound, the value of m:", "choices": {"A": "gets closer and closer to 0.", "B": "gets closer and closer to 1.", "C": "gets closer and closer to 3.", "D": "remains constant.", "E": "gets larger and larger."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. The book Fahrenheit 451 by Ray Bradbury is about a society in which all books are banned and burned. The title of the book gives the approximate temperature at which paper starts to burn. Since Fahrenheit, F, and Celsius, C, temperatures are related by the formula C = (F - 32), which of the following would make an equivalent title for the book?", "choices": {"A": "Celsius 219", "B": "Celsius 233", "C": "Celsius 268", "D": "Celsius 754", "E": "Celsius 844"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. The length of a rectangle is 6 inches longer than the width. If the perimeter of the rectangle is 48 inches, what is the width, in inches?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "9", "C": "15", "D": "21", "E": "27"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. What are all the solutions for x if 2x2 - 3x - 20 = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "x = -20 only", "B": "x = -5 or x = 2", "C": "x = -4 or x =", "D": "x =  or x = 4", "E": "x = -2 or x = 5"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. In Terell's history class, all tests count equally. So far. Terell has taken 2 of the 3 tests in history and earned scores of 93% and 82%, respectively. What is the minimum percent Terell needs on the third test to have a test average of at least 85% ?", "choices": {"A": "89% ", "B": "88% ", "C": "87% ", "D": "83% ", "E": "80% "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. If a, b, and c are positive integers such that ab = x and cb = y, then xy = ?", "choices": {"A": "acb", "B": "ac2b", "C": "(ac)b", "D": "(ac)2b", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. What is the area, in square inches, of a circle with a diameter equal to 10 inches ?", "choices": {"A": "100", "B": "25", "C": "10\u03c0", "D": "25\u03c0", "E": "100\u03c0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. To get a driver's license, an applicant must pass a written test and a driving test. Past records show that 80% of the applicants pass the written test and 60% of those who have passed the written test pass the driving test. Based on these figures, how many applicants in a random group of 1,000 applicants would you expect to get driver's licenses?", "choices": {"A": "200", "B": "480", "C": "600", "D": "750", "E": "800"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. If sin A = , then which of the following could be tan A ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "1", "D": "", "E": "4"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. If x is any number other than 4 and 5, then \uff1d \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "-20", "B": "-1", "C": "0", "D": "1", "E": "20"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Triangle \u25b3ABC is similar to \u25b3DEF. AB is 8 inches long, BC is 10 inches long, and AC is 16 inches long. If the longest side of \u25b3DEF is 40 inches long, what is the perimeter, in inches, of \u25b3DEF?", "choices": {"A": "74", "B": "85", "C": "90", "D": "136", "E": "170"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Sides AB, BC, CD, and DA of square ABCD have midpoints L, M, N, and K, as shown below. If AB is 6 inches long, what is the area, in square inches, of the shaded region?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "9", "D": "", "E": "18"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. In the figure below, AC is a diameter of the circle, B is a point on the circle, and AB \u224c BC .  What is the degree measure of \u2220ABC ?", "choices": {"A": "45\u00b0", "B": "60\u00b0", "C": "75\u00b0", "D": "90\u00b0", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what are the coordinates of the midpoint of a line segment with endpoints (-1, 3) and (2, 7) ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "(1, 4)", "E": "(3, 4)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. In a downhill ski race, Margo posted a time of 2 minutes and 24 seconds for a course 1.2 miles long. About how many miles per hour did she average for the race?", "choices": {"A": "60", "B": "30", "C": "20", "D": "3", "E": "2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. For the 2 functions f(x) and g(x), tables of values are shown below. What is the value of g(f(3))?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "-3", "C": "-1", "D": "2", "E": "7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. For positive real numbers x, y, and z, which of the following expressions is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. A formula for the area of a rhombus is A = d1d2, where d1 and d2 are the lengths of the diagonals. Which of the following is an expression for d2 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2(A - d1)", "E": "A - "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. The line graphed below shows the predicted gasoline use for a certain car. Which of the following is the closest estimate of this car's predicted rate of gasoline use, in miles per gallon?", "choices": {"A": "28", "B": "30", "C": "33", "D": "35", "E": "40"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. The graph of y = ax2 + bx + c in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane is shown below.When y = 0, which of the following best describes the solution set for x ?", "choices": {"A": "2 real solutions", "B": "1 double real solution only", "C": "1 real and 1 imaginary solution", "D": "1 double imaginary solution only", "E": "2 imaginary solutions"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. If IyI = y + 6, then y = ?", "choices": {"A": "-12", "B": "-6", "C": "-3", "D": "0", "E": "6"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. What fraction lies exactly halfway between  and  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. Elliott writes a check for $15. He records the check in his check register, which up to this time has shown the correct balance. When figuring his new balance, he accidentally adds $15 instead of subtracting. The balance in his check register now shows:", "choices": {"A": "$30 less than it should.", "B": "$15 less than it should.", "C": "the correct amount.", "D": "$15 more than it should.", "E": "$30 more than it should."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. Six plants, each of a different plant type, are to be arranged on a display shelf's 6 spots. If each spot must have a plant, in how many different arrangements can the plants be placed?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "21", "C": "30", "D": "36", "E": "720"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the distance between the points (3, -4) and (-5, 2) ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "6", "C": "8", "D": "10", "E": "14"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. A formula for the volume, V, of a right circular cylinder is V = \u03c0r2h, where r is the radius and h is the height. The cylindrical tank shown below has radius 5 meters and height 4 meters and is filled with water.If 1 cubic meter of water weighs approximately 2,205 pounds, then the weight, in pounds, of the water in the tank is:", "choices": {"A": "less than 200,000.", "B": "between 200,000 and 400,000.", "C": "between 400,000 and 600,000.", "D": "between 600,000 and 800,000.", "E": "more than 800,000."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. What are the values of \u03b8, between 0\u00b0 and 360 \u00b0 , when tan \u03b8 = -1 ?", "choices": {"A": "225\u00b0 and 315\u00b0 only", "B": "135\u00b0 and 315\u00b0 only", "C": "135\u00b0 and 225\u00b0 only", "D": "45\u00b0 and 135\u00b0 only", "E": "45\u00b0, 135\u00b0 , 225\u00b0, and 315\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Which of the following is an equation of a circle with its center at (3, 4) and tangent to the x-axis in the standard(x, y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "(x - 3)2 + (y - 4)2 = 16", "B": "(x - 4)2 + (y - 3)2 = 16", "C": "(x - 4)2 + (y - 3)2 = 9", "D": "(x - 3)2 + (y - 4)2 = 9", "E": "(x + 4)2 + (y + 3)2 = 16"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Which of the following best represents the graph of y \u2264 ax + b for some positive a and negative b ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. One of the graphs below is that of y = A sin \u03b8 for \u03b8 between 0 and 6.28 radians, where A is a constant. Which graph?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. In the figure below, D, E, and F are the midpoints of the sides AB, BC, and AC, respectively. If the measure of \u2220BCA is 20\u00b0, and the measure of \u2220BAC is 60\u00b0, what is the sum of the measures of \u2220DFE and \u2220FED ?", "choices": {"A": "60\u00b0", "B": "80\u00b0", "C": "100\u00b0", "D": "120\u00b0", "E": "160\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. A formula for the surface area (A) of the rectangular solid shown below is A = 2lw + 2lh + 2wh where l represents length; w, width; and h, height. By doubling each of the dimensions (l, w, and h), the surface area will be multiplied by what factor?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": "6", "D": "8", "E": "12"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. If sin x =  and cos x = , then sec x = ?", "choices": {"A": "-2", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. In a rhombus, all 4 sides are the same length. Rhombus ABCD below has vertices at A(0, 0) and C(4, 6). What is the slope of diagonal BD ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. Yvette earned a score of 56 on a recent 25-question multiple-choice exam. The scoring for the exam was +6 for each correct answer, -2 for each incorrect answer, and 0 for each unanswered question. What is the maximum number of questions Yvette could have answered correctly?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "10", "C": "11", "D": "13", "E": "14"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, the graphs of the 3 equations x - 1 = 0, y + 2 = 0, and x + y = 4 form the boundary of a triangle. What is the area of this triangle, expressed in square coordinate units?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "8", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}]}